armandkassaikoupai@gmail.com

French Nationality

+33 6 64 32 24 52

PROFILE

French PhD student working on data related challenges with academic experience in Deep Learning, notably as an AI Scientist and Researcher in Radar fusion at the University of Bristol and as a PhD student at Sorbonne Université. I am particularly interested in new methods to improve generalization of neural networks, notably for solving physical systems.

EDUCATION

Sorbonne Université – MLIA team at ISIR

Paris, France

2022 - Now

2020 - 2021

PhD student under the supervision of Patrick Gallinari

• Topic: Out-of-distribution generalization: learning to generalize neural PDE solvers to unseen parameters

Bristol, United Kingdom

Master of Science

University of Bristol

Grade: Distinction

Relevant Coursework: Statistical Computing and Empircal Methods (R programming), Large-Scale Data Engineering(AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner), Introduction to Artificial Intelligence (Python), Text Analytics (Python), Visual Analytics (Python), and Technology/Innovation/Business/Society (TIBS)

École Nationale Supérieure de l'électronique et de ses applications, ENSEA

Cergy-Pontoise, France

2018 – 2020

A leading engineering school in electronical and computing engineering ("Grande École")

Master of Electrical and Computing Engineering / Diplôme d'Ingénieur

Grade: First Class

 Relevant Coursework: Measure and Probability Theory, Fourier Analysis, C programming, Signal processing (Matlab), Random Signal Processing (Matlab), Statistics and optimisation, Object-oriented programming (JAVA), Information Theory and multimedia compression (Matlab).

Classe préparatoire aux grandes écoles d'ingéneur

Paris, France

2016 - 2018

Two competitive years studying sciences subjects to be prepared for a nationwide exam

Grade: First Class

Relevant Coursework: Mathematics, Physics, Chemistry, Science engineering, Computing (Python & SQL), Philosophy

WORK EXPERIENCE

University of Bristol

Bristol, United Kingdom

Research Scientist and Researcher in Radar Fusion

November 2021 – May 2022

Working for the OPERA project under the supervision of Robert Piechocki, professor of Wireless Systems at the University of Bristol, in collaboration with UCL and the University of Oxford.

- Build data pipelines to process raw time series data from different sensors and get different image feature representations using signal processing techniques;
- Research and development of software models for sensor and image features fusion in Python, notably using vision transformers with a fully supervised and a self-supervised approach;
- Contribute to written reports and technical publications for the OPERA project.

SustainEcho Data Engineer Intern

Paris, France

The first platform that uses AI to automate the Carbon Footprint of construction projects directly from measurements.

- Benchmark of the best ontologies and data cleaning and processing of the ConceptNet's data (Python);
- Build a database from INSEE, ConceptNet and SustainEcho's data using ElasticSearch;
- Query the database and create links between similar content using an n-gram model;
- Creation of a graph Database using the links created, on *Neo4j*.

Renault Group Signal Processing Intern

Guyancourt, France

May 2020 – August 2020

July 2019 – August 2019

French multinational automobile manufacturer established in 1899. Assisted the R&D team specialized in Sound and NVH (Noise vibration and harshness).

- Checked the adequacy of the Arkamys signal processing solution to Renault product requirements;
- Analyzed and corrected their loudness corrector by modelling signals on Matlab.

PUBLICATIONS

Self-supervised multimodal fusion transformer for passive activity recognition

IET Wireless Sensor Systems

2022

Armand K Koupai, Mohammud J Bocus, Raul Santos-Rodriguez, Robert J Piechocki, Ryan McConville

Preprint

Alex Iacob, Pedro PB Gusmão, Nicholas D Lane, Armand K Koupai, Mohammud J Bocus, Raúl Santos-Rodríguez, Robert J Piechocki, Ryan McConville

2022

• Operator learning with neural fields: Tackling PDEs on general geometries
Louis Serrano, Lise Le Boudec, Armand Kassaï Koupaï, Thomas X Wang, Yuan Yin,
Jean-Noël Vittaut, Patrick Gallinari

NeurIPS Conference

ICLR Workshop 2024

 Learn to adapt Parametric Solvers under incomplete Physics Armand Kassaï Koupaï, Yuan Yin, Patrick Gallinari

Privacy in Multimodal Federated Human Activity Recognition

<u>INTERESTS</u>

Trips – Europe, North America, Asia and North Africa

Bodybuilding – 2 years

Guitar – 7 years

Chess-7 years